Guide to the Erica Jong papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series IV: Erica Jong Files--as organized by Jong, 1970-2008
  - Subseries IV.2: Project Files, 1970-1993
    - "Sara Davidson: Loose Change," 1977 (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - Saturday Review, 1981-1984 (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - "The Seamy Side of the Author's Life," Undated (Box 86, Folder 19)
    - "Selleck," 1983-1985 (Box 86, Folder 20)
    - SHE Magazine, 1988 (Box 86, Folder 21)
    - "Solitude," 1979 (Box 86, Folder 22)
    - "Speaking of Love," 1977 (Box 86, Folder 23)
    - "Special Edition-Ch 13," 1978-1980 (Box 86, Folder 24)
    - "The Square Root of Writing (essay)," Undated (Box 86, Folder 25)
    - "The Strange Case of Philip Roth," Undated (Box 86, Folder 26)
    - "Succeed at Your Own Risk," 1975 (Box 86, Folder 27)
    - "Sweet Smutty Schlock," 1976 (Box 86, Folder 28)
    - "Three Sisters," 1972 (Box 86, Folder 29)
    - "Towards a Truce Bt. The Sexes (Andrea Dworkin)," 1978-1988, (3 Folders) (Box 86, Folder 30 to 32)
    - "Treatments--Synop."
      - "Demetra Z.: A Novel," Undated (Box 86, Folder 33)
      - "The Scam: A Caper Novel," Undated (Box 86, Folder 34)
      - "Some Object of Love: A Novel," Undated (Box 86, Folder 35)
    - TV Guide (Proposed piece)," 1981-1982 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Uncollected Articles and Reviews, Undated (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - "UNITAR," 1980-1981 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - "Unpub. Short Stor." 1972-1975, Undated, (2 Folders) (Box 87, Folder 4 to 5)
    - "Unpublished Work," Undated (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Vanity Fair, 1986 (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - VIVA, 1976 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Vogue, 1980-1987 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Vogue (Witch Piece), 1982 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Vogue--Condé Nast--Mademoiselle, 1965-1977 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - "Walt Whitman Review," 1980 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - "Washington Post," 1986 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - "Wendy Martin Interview," 1981 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - "Whatever Happened to the Zipless Fuck?" 1989 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - "Who's Who in Society," 1988-1989 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - "Woman's Day," 1976 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - "Woman's Forum, 1987-1989 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - "Working Woman," 1988 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - "Writer as Sexual Guru," Undated (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - "Writer's Book of Days," 1977 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Writer's Digest, 1980-1981 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - "Writer's Guild of America," 1973-1989 (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - "Writer's Organizations," 1972-1989, (3 Folders) (Box 87, Folder 24 to 26)
    - "Writing a First Novel," 1974 (Box 87, Folder 27)
    - "Yaddo," Undated (Box 87, Folder 28)
    - "You Have to Be Liberated to Laugh," 1980 (Box 87, Folder 29)
  - Subseries IV.3: Business Files, 1974-1995
    Jong's business files, which were received labeled and organized, have been kept intact. These files include correspondence and documents pertaining to court cases such as Jong v. Sterling Lord, and the case over the title of Megan's Book of Divorce. Also here are book contracts, publishing agreements, and memoranda, in addition to documents on multimedia projects
    - "General," 1983-1988 (Box 87, Folder 30)
    - "Fanny," 1978-1986 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Legal Correspondence, 1970s-1995
      - General, 1970s-1980s, (4 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 2 to 5)
      - Burrows, Ken, 1992-1995 (Box 88, Folder 6)
      - Burrows, Ken, 1992-1995 (Box 88, Folder 7)
      - "Old Files" [Restricted until 2040]
        - General, 1981-1989 (2 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 8 to 9)
        - "Foreign Royalties Split Letters," 1988 (2 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 10 to 11)
        - "Joan Stein Haus," 1984, 1987 (Box 88, Folder 12)
        - "Norman Solovey," 1988-1989 (Box 88, Folder 13)
        - "Program Corporation of America," 1984-1987 (Box 88, Folder 14)
        - "Requests-Speaking Sent to Lecture Agt," 1985-1987 (Box 88, Folder 15)
        - "Spoken Arts," 1976-1977 (Box 88, Folder 16)
        - "Tag," 1988 (Box 88, Folder 17)
      - "Victor, Ed," 1989-1994 (2 Folders) (Box 88, Folder 18)
      - "Victor, Ed", 1989-1994 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - "Literary Agent", 1974-1988
      - "Correspondence, Agreements, Memoranda, Miscellaneous," 1984-1988 (3 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 2 to 4)
      - "Court Papers," 1986 (Box 89, Folder 5)
      - "Deposition of Erica Jong + Exhibits," 1986, (2 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 6 to 7)
    - "Megan's Book of Divorce", 1983-1985
      - General, 1987 (Box 89, Folder 8)
      - "Correspondence, Court Papers, Client's Papers, Memoranda, Miscellaneous," 1983-1985, (3 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 9 to 11)
      - "Documents produced by NAL re Koster Deposition," 1985, (2 Folders) (Box 89, Folder 12 to 13)
    - "Parachutes & Kisses," 1982-1986 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - "Parachutes & Kisses," 1982-1986 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - "Parties," 1993-1995 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - "Playboy TV Pilot," 1980-1984, (4 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 3 to 6)
    - "Serenissima," 1986-1987 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - "Travel," 1995 (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Subseries IV. 4: Publication Files, 1970-1993
    This subseries consists of reviews, publicity tour details, invitations for readings, contracts, proposals for multimedia adaptation projects, and other projects inspired by Jong's publications.
    - List of A to Z Files, 2011 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - A to Z, 1972-1987 (7 Folders) (Box 90, Folder 10 to 16)
    - A to Z, 1972-1987 (7 Folders) (Box 91, Folder 1 to 7)
    - Any Woman's Blues, 1989-1993, (5 Folders) (Box 91, Folder 8 to 12)
    - Becoming Light, 1989-1992 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Fruits & Vegetables, 1970-1971 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - How to Save Your Own Life, 1975, 1990, 1993 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Ordinary Miracles, 1983-1984, (2 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 3 to 4)
    - Parachutes & Kisses, 1982-1989 (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Serenissima, 1986-1993 (4 of 6 Folders) (Box 92, Folder 6 to 11)
    - Witches, 1979-1986
      - "Artist Jos A. Smith," 1979, Undated (includes slides) (Box 92, Folder 12)
      - Kathy Acker, "Hello, I'm Erica Jong," 1982 (Box 92, Folder 13)
      - "Merchandising," 1981 (Box 92, Folder 14)
      - "NAL Witches," 1981-1984 (Box 92, Folder 15)
      - "Publicity, Promotion," 1981-1986 (Box 92, Folder 16)
      - "Witches," 1981-1986 (Box 92, Folder 17 to 20)
      - "Witches," 1981-1986 (3 Folders) (Box 93, Folder 1 to 3)
- Series V: Printed Material, 1963-2011
  Gathered in this series are books, clippings, magazines, journals, and other published materials related to Jong and her work, or reflecting Jong's professional and/or personal interests.
  - General, 1963-1988 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Behind His Mask, 1971 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Beloit Reprints, 1969 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Books and Journals
    - List of, 2011 (Box 93, Folder 7)
    - Books and Journals--Various, 1960s-1990s (Box 102)
    - "Seventeen Warnings in Search of a Feminist Poem"--The Nation, 1971 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Clippings
    - Luce Press
      - 1980-1988 (Box 93, Folder 9 to 10)
      - 1970s-1980s (1 Small Box) (Box 93)
    - Reviews, 1973 (Box 93, Folder 11)
    - With Letters and Notes, 1976-1999 (2 Folders) (Box 93, Folder 12 to 13)
    - Scrapbook, 1981-1982 (Box 100, Folder 7)
    - Columbia Forum, 1974-1985 (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Magazine Interview, 1989 (Box 100, Folder 8)
  - Publicity Posters, 1970s-1980s (Box 101, Folder 4)
  - Reading Announcements and Flyers (Box 93, Folder 15)
  - Rimbaud, 1976-1977 (Box 93, Folder 16)
- Series VI: Audio/Visual Materials, 1962-2000
  The materials in this series consist primarily of audio cassette tapes and VHS tapes, along with some photographs, reel-to-reel tapes and other media. The cassette tapes include poetry readings, interviews, and audio transcripts of Jong's published works, while the VHS tapes tend to feature Jong's multiple television appearances, as well as some personal recordings.
  Four audio cassette tapes of Jong interviewing Henry Miller have been transferred to Audio CDs for preservation and access.
  - Audio Cassette Tapes, 1972-1990 (Box 94)
    - General, 1970s-1989, undated (20 tapes) (Box 94)
    - Black Box Audio Tapes, 1972-1975 (6 cassettes, with liner notes) (Box 94)
    - Henry Miller, 1979-1980
      - Conversation with Henry Miller--Barbara Kraft, 1979 (Box 94)
      - Henry Miller & Marcel Marceau, Undated (3 tapes) (Box 94)
      - Memorial Service, 1980 (Box 94)
      - Personal Interviews, 1970s (4 tapes and 6 CDs) (Box 94)
    - Interviews and Readings, 1977-1990 (52 Tapes) (Box 94)
    - Mini Cassette Tapes, 1990s, Undated (9 tapes) (Box 94)
  - Jos A Smith Prints, 1980 (Box 100, Folder 9)
  - Other Media, 1977 (Box 95)
  - Conversations about Writing,Undated (Box 95)
  - Erica Jong and Yolanda Nava on Sunday Show, undated (Box 95)
  - Tonight Show, 1977 (Box 95)
  - Photographs, 1962-1984 (Box 96)
    - General, 1970s-1980s (2 Folders) (Box 96, Folder 1 to 2)
    - Bailey, Pearl, Undated (Box 96, Folder 3)
    - Contact Sheets, 1974 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Early, Undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
    - "Elephant Pix-Big Apple Circus," Undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - Erica Jong and Henry Miller, 1976 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Mark Morrow Barnard Shots, 1984 (with letter and Robert Penn Warren) (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Negative with Poem, Undated (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Portraits of Erica Jong, 1970s-1980s (4 Folders) (Box 96, Folder 9 to 12)
    - Portraits of Erica Jong, 1962-1970s (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Publicity, 1980 (Box 96, Folder 13)
    - Venice Souvenir Box, 1982 (Box 102)
    - Vogue, 1980 (Box 96, Folder 13)
    - Drawn on Giant Cloth, Undated (Box 100, Folder 12)
  - Reels
    - "Erica reading on TV," 1965 (with letter) (Box 95)
    - Poets and Writers, Undated (Box 95)
  - VHS Tapes, 1987-2000 (Box 97, 98, 99)
    - List of VHS Tapes in 97-99, 2011 (Box 97, 98, 99)
    - Tapes, 1987-2000 (Box 97, 98, 99)